鬼神復活のため。=Conspiring to revive the Kishin…
死武専に忍び寄る。=She snuck into the DWMA.
魔女。メデューサの陰謀。The witch; Medusa’s Plot. 
物語がクライマックス。=The tale reaches its climax!

行くよ、ソウル！ Let’s do this, Soul!
おう！=Yeah!
タッチペン共鳴アクション=Resonate using the stylus!*I have no idea how to make this work in English Xd
(red and white text): 十字キーキでフィールドを移動=Use the D-Pad to explore maps.
(voice):十字キーでキャラクターを移動しフィールドを移動するの=Use the D-Pad to control your character and move across maps.
(small note):※ゲーム画面は開発中のものです。画面はハメコミ合成です。=This ad was created whilst the game was still under development. Footage may not represent the final version.
(red and white text): タッチペンで敵を攻撃！=Attack using the stylus!
(voice):タッチペンで敵を攻撃し軌道を描いて連続コンボを繰り出せる=Use the stylus to attack enemies and draw shapes to create continuous combos.

エ、このアイテム=Hm? That icon?
(red and white text): キャラクターセンシステム=Character change system.
状況に応じてキャラを使い分ける=Use different characters depending on the situation.
(blue text): 敵を滅する魔鎌の閃！=Wield a destructive magic scythe!
(voice):我々なぎ払いマカ＆ソウル=Moving down foes… Maka and Soul!
(yellow text): 変幻自在の武器攻撃！=Attack with a transforming weapon!
(voice):変幻自在の魔暗器攻撃で敵を翻弄、ブラック☆スター＆椿=Making light work of enemies with his transforming Magic Dark Arm weapon… Black☆Star and Tsubaki!
(pink text): ロックオンして敵を一掃！=Lock on and wipe out the enemies!
(voice):遠くの敵もCOOLに狙撃二丁魔拳銃の使い手、キッド＆トンプソン姉妹=Cooly sniping distant enemies, Demon Twin Guns’ user… Kid and the Thompson Sisters!
3組の特徴を生かして迫りくるメデューサの陰謀に立ち向かい。=Utilitise the specialities of these three teams to oppose the imminent threat of Medusa’s Plot.

魂の共鳴システム=Soul Resonance System
武器と職人は二人に一つ=Meister and Weapon become one.
ゲージを溜めて、必殺を出せ=Fill the gauge to use special moves.
行くぜ、マカ=Let’s go, Maka!
魔女狩り=Witch-Hunt!

(text):死武専から与えられれる課題を遂行=Take on missions given by the DWMA.
(voice):死武専から与えられれる課題を遂行クリアーして、物語を進むの=Clear missions given by the DWMA to move the story along.
通信で友達と協力したり、=Compete with friends using the multiplayer mode,
(text):ステージ上に散らばるカードゲット=Collect cards hidden throughout the levels
ステージ上に散らばるカードをゲットしたり=and collect the cards hidden throughout each level.
これでは男男のＣＯＯＬ度も上がれてもいいや=With this, my coolness level will be off the charts!*

姿・形が問題じゃねェ、問題なのは"魂"さ=In the end the shape and form don't matter at all, it's only the “soul” that matters.
お前の魂をいただく。=Your soul is mine!
ニンテンドーDS用ソフト。メデューサの陰謀 =Soul Eater: Medusa’s Plot for Nintendo DS.
10月23日発売予定。=English patch out now!

(text):予約特典=Pre-order bonus
(text):デス・ザ・キッド　スケートボード型キーチェーン=A keyring of Death the Kid’s skateboard.
予約特典はスケートボード型キーチェーン=The pre-order bonus is a keyring of Death the Kid’s skateboard.
Ｃ-ＣＯＯＬだそう。=T-that’s pretty cool.
